Finding Aid for the Southern California Chapter of the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America Records LSC.0149
UCLA Library Special Collections
Southern California Chapter of the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America records
1949-1982
UCLA Library Special Collections
Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America. Southern California Chapter
LSC.0149
8.5 Linear Feet (17 boxes and 2 oversize boxes)
The Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America was founded in 1949 to encourage interest in rare books and manuscripts and to maintain the highest standards in the antiquarian book trade. The collection consists of the Southern California Chapter files of the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America (1949-80), directories, newsletters, bylaws, programs and posters.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Philip S. Brown, 1952.
Gift of Glen Dawson, 1982.
Gift of George Allen, 1982.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9963866393606533
History
The Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America was founded in 1949 to encourage interest in rare books and manuscripts and to maintain the highest standards in the antiquarian book trade; it promotes exhibitions of books and related materials, and lectures on subjects of interest to book collectors; members engage in the sale, purchase, and appraisal of antiquarian books and manuscripts. The Southern California chapter encompasses the area from Santa Barbara to San Diego.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of Southern California Chapter files of the Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America (1949-80), directories, newsletters, bylaws, programs, posters, as well as some material on the national and international organizations.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Southern California chapter files, 1949-80 (Boxes 1-7).
Treasurer's reports, 1952-70 (Box 8).
History, reminiscences, miscellaneous papers (Box 9).
Glen Dawson's files (Box 10).
Ephemera, book fair programs, bylaws (Box 11).
ABAA national (Box 12).
International League of Antiquarian Booksellers (ILAB) (Box 13).
ABA England (Box 14).
ABAA directories, membership (Box 15).
Publications (Box 16).
Alphabooks, catalogs, correspondence (Box 17).
Mr. Pickwick figure (Box 18).
California book fair posters (Box 19).
Booksellers and bookselling -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America.Southern California Chapter--Archives
- Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America, Southern California Chapter
  - Files, v.d.
    - 1949-1953., 15 folders. (Box 1)
    - 1954-1965., 24 folders. (Box 2)
    - 1965-1967., 19 folders. (Box 3)
    - 1967., 16 folders. (Box 4)
    - 1968-1973., 32 folders. (Box 5)
    - 1973-1974., 12 folders. (Box 6)
    - 1976-1980., 12 folders. (Box 7)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1952-1970.; 5 folders. (Box 8)
  - History, reminiscences, miscellaneous papers., 10 folders. (Box 9)
    Scope and Contents note
    Including directories, secretarial files, photographs.
  - Glen Dawson's files., 4 folders. (Box 10)
  - Ephemera, book fair programs, bylaws, unsorted files, 1969-1973.; 8 folders. (Box 11)
  - Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America, National, including files, Bylaws, miscellaneous, directories., 1969-1978.; 8 folders. (Box 12)
  - International League of Antiquarian Booksellers (ILAB), including correspondence, and Newsletter, 1949-1976 1959-1977.; 7 folders. (Box 13)
  - Antiquarian Bookseller's Association, England, 1966-1976.; 3 folders. (Box 14)
  - Antiquarian Booksellers Center, New York, 1973-1975.; 2 folders. (Box 14)
- California Book Fair Posters, 1961-1982
  General note
  (Manager of Fair: Harry Levinson)
  - (1st California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1961, November 11-13 (Box 19)
  - (2nd California). San Francisco: Hotel St. Francis., 1962, October 5-7 (Box 19)
  - (3rd California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1963, October 30-November 1 (Box 19)
  - (4th California). San Francisco: Sheraton-Palace Hotel., 1964, October 15-17 (Box 19)
  - (5th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1965, November 11-13 (Box 19)
  - (6th California). San Francisco: Sheraton Palace Hotel., 1966, October 27-29 (Box 19)
  - (7th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1970, October 15-17 (Box 19)
  - (8th California). San Francisco: St. Francis Hotel., 1972, September 21-23 (Box 19)
  - (9th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1974, October 3-5 (Box 19)
  - (10th California). San Francisco: Fairmont Hotel., 1976, September 16-18 (Box 19)
  - (11th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1978, February 2-4 (Box 19)
  - (13th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1980, February 7-9 (Box 19)
  - (14th California). San Francisco: The Showplace., 1981, January 29-February 1 (Box 19)
  - (15th California). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1982, February 18-20 (Box 19)
  - (2nd International). Los Angeles: Ambassador Hotel., 1967, September 21-23 (Box 19)
- UCLA Book Fair Posters
  - Los Angeles: 2nd Floor Lounge, Ackerman Student Union., 1977, October 23. (Box 19)
  - Los Angeles: Grand Ballroom, Ackerman Student Union., 1979, October 27-28. (Box 19)
  - Los Angeles: Grand Ballroom, Ackerman Student Union., 1981, October 24-25. (Box 19)
- Additions
  - Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America Regional. Directories., 1 folder. 22 items. (Box 15)
    Includes Middle Atlantic, Northern/Southern California, Midwest.
  - Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America National. Membership lists., 1 folder. 8 items. (Box 15)
    1967, 1968, 1972, 1974, 1977, 1979 membership lists, and Catalogue of the Library of Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America.
  - Antiquarian Booksellers Association of America - Other Countries., 1 folder. 20 items. (Box 15)
    Directories and membership lists for England, France, Germany, Japan, 1960-1969.
  - Book Fair Programs, 1967-1980.; 1 folder. 7 items. (Box 15)
  - International League of Antiquarian Booksellers (ILAB)., 1 folder. 4 items. (Box 15)
    Import/export regulations, rules, directory, programs.
  - Antiquarian Bookseller's Association (International)., 1 folder. 5 items. (Box 15)
    Objects and rules (1956), list of members - 1967, 1970, 1972, 1974.
  - Publications
    - Directory of Western Book Publishing and Related Supplies and Services. Los Angeles, Southern California Bookbuilders, c. 1973.; 35pp. (Box 16)
    - Syndicat de la Librarie Ancienne et Moderne. Liste Officielle des Membres. Paris, Hotel du Cercle de la Librarie, 1964.; 112pp. (Box 16)
    - Book Dealers in North America. A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books in Canada and the United States of America. 1968-1970. London: Sheppard Press, c., 197pp. (Box 16)
    - A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books in the British Isles, 1960-1962. London: Sheppard Press, c. 1961.; 224pp. (Box 16)
    - A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books in the British Isles, 1972-1974. London: Sheppard Press, c. 1972.; 269pp. (Box 16)
    - European Bookdealers. A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books on the continent of Europe. London: Sheppard Press, c. 1967.; 197pp. (Box 16)
    - European Bookdealers. A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books on the continent of Europe. 1964-1966., c. 1965.; 200pp. (Box 16)
    - European Bookdealers. A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books on the continent of Europe. 1969-1971. With supplement, c. 1969.; 264pp. (Box 16)
    - European Bookdealers. A Directory of Dealers in Secondhand and Antiquarian Books on the continent of Europe. 1973-1975., c. 1973.; 290pp. (Box 16)
    - 1971 Annual Directory of Booksellers in the British Isles Specialising in Antiquarian and Out-of-Print Books. London: Clique Limited, c. 1971.; 128pp. (Box 16)
  - Additions, January 1986
    - Alphabooks. 18046 Ventura Blvd., Encino
      - Business card., 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Dawson's Book Shop. 627 Grand Ave., Los Angeles
      - Catalogue no.227. One Hundred and One Rare Books., 1948.; 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Milton Hammer Rare Books. 819 Anacapa St., Santa Barbara
      - Catalog no.1, Literature., 1971.; 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Catalog no.5. Americana., 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Notecard., 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Photographs., 3 items. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Doris Harris Autographs. 1300 S. Beacon St., San Pedro; 5410 Wilshire Blvd., Los Angeles
      - Catalog no.1, August 1956. (Box 17, Folder 4)
        Front cover only.
      - Catalog no.26, 1981.; 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Letter to Muir Dawson. Los Angeles, Steptember 11, 1981.; 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Needham Book Finders. 2317 Westwood Blvd., Los Angeles
      - Letter to Muir Dawson from Stanley Kurman. Los Angeles, September 24, 1981.; 1 item. With photograph enclosed. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Maurice F. Neville Rare Books. 835 South Laguna St., Santa Barbara
      - Catalog no.1, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Notecards., 2 items. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Pickwick Book Shop. Hollywood Blvd., Hollywood. (Box ** 18)
  - 3-dimensional representation of Mr. Pickwick, trademark of the Pickwick Bookshop., Approximately 46 ×; 45 cm. Metal figure, painted. Depth: 7 cm. (Box ** 18)
    Gift of Louis Epstein, 1985.